David Ibanez

UI/UX Designer

36 years old Resident visa

www.davidibanez.com dibanez@rocketmail.com Hino-shi, Tokyo-to

Tools

Sketch, Adobe Creative Suite, InVision, Vs code, Tableau, Google Analytics, Google Data Studio

Skills

Design

Interface Design, Web design, user flows, Prototyping, Wireframes, Visual Design, Illustration, Design Systems

User Research

Business intelligence, Personas

Programing

HTML, CSS/SASS, JQuery, React, Git versioning

Languages

English

Business level, TOEIC: 925/990

Japanese

Business level, JLPT N2: 116/180

Profile

I'm a UI/UX designer with 8 years of experience.

My knowledge of Frontend development helps me efficiently communicate my designs to developers. I'm currently looking to join an existing design team in a company that trusts the design process to deliver meaningful and measurable changes to their customers.

Experience

UI/UX Designer For Comvex

Sept 2016 to present in Japan

- Worked with the Backend, Frontend team, and the production manager to conceptualized and design the new version of the company's main product.
- Improved design quality, consistency, and delivery time by creating a design system, and a documentation site for the company's main product.
- Helped improve the company decision-making process by collecting, and sharing important user and business-related metrics.

Freelance Web Designer/Front-End-Developer

Sept 2015 to July 2016 in Japan

- Designed and developed a high-fidelity web application prototype for pharmaceutical wholesalers using AngularJS and the MEAN stack.
- Designed and developed the E-Commerce website ELSA for Salem Laboratory using Odoo EPR/CRM.
- Banding and design for OSIS a French IT service company specializing in open source technologies.

Web Designer/Front-End-Developer For E.T.I

July 2013 to August 2015 in France

- Designed, developed, and maintained a variety of product, corporate, and E-Commerce websites as well as an in-house CMS.
- Introduce the company to modern workflows including assets optimization and automation via grunt, a custom BEM implementation via Sass.

Web Designer For La Bonne Agence

May 2012 to September 2012 in France

- Designed marketing materials for Orange Music Festival, a promotional campaign organized by Orange, the world's 7th largest mobile operator.
- Designed and developed the front-end of the Nanoatschool website for MINATEC, an international campus for micro and nanotechnology research, home to 3,000 researchers, and 1,200 students.

Education

Web Design & Conception

2011 - 2012 Supcréa Design School in France

Coursework included methodology and project management, visual semiotics, graphic expression techniques, composition, typography, programming, and web design.

Intensive Japanese Lessons

2009 - 2010 OLJ in Japan

Immersed in a full year of Intensive Japanese lessons 4 hours a day, 5 days a week. At the end of my studies, I was able to successfully pass the JLPT N2 test.

Associate's Degree In Economics And Accounting

2007 Pierre Mendès-France Université in France

Coursework included Law Economics, Accounting, Statistics, Social Sciences, and English.